cartrader.com.na 2013-08-06

# privacy-policy-for-namibia

By using Car Trader, you permit the collection and use of your personal information as outlined below and you signify your agreement to this Privacy Policy (last updated on 29th April 2013). If you do not agree with these terms, you should not use Car Trader.

## ABOUT CAT TRADER PRIVACY POLICY

1.1 Our website www.CarTrader.com.na, all the webpage’s containing that address ("Car Trader") and the services provided on Car Trader are operated by Trader Publishing Limited with a registered office at : ………………………………………………………. ("we", "us" and "our"). Car Trader allows users to search advertisements posted on Car Trader for new and used vehicles ("Vehicles"). Car Trader also allows users, both private sellers and professional trade advertisers to register with Car Trader ("Advertisers"), and to place advertisements for the sale of Vehicles.

1.2 This policy, together with our Terms and Conditions and any other documents referred to in them, set out the basis on which any personal data we collect from you, or that you provide to us, will be processed by us. Please read the following carefully to understand our views and practices regarding your personal data and how we will treat it.

### How we collect Information on Car Trader:

2.1 You can browse Car Trader without telling us who you are or revealing any personal information about yourself.

2.2 When registering as an Advertiser, responding to an advertisement via Car Trader or during your time as an Advertiser or user of Car Trader you may be asked to provide information to us. By agreeing to this Policy you agree that we have informed you about ollecting information from you whether the information that you may provide to us will be accessible to other users of Car Trader, other Advertisers or by third parties so that you are in a position to take an informed decision on whether to provide the information to us.

2.3 We may collect and process the following data about you:

2.3.1 if you contact us, we may keep a record of that correspondence;

2.3.2 information that you submit in response to an advertisement or when communicating with an Advertiser;

2.3.3 in order to register as an Advertiser, we will require you to supply your name, email address, contact telephone number, and postal address, street address:

2.3.4 in order to ensure the information supplied to us is held securely we may occasionally request proof of identity before allowing access to your personal information;

2.3.5 if you place an advertisement on Car Trader, we will require vehicle registration details, a telephone number, (either a landline or a mobile number) and an email address;

2.3.6 if you place an advertisement on Car Trader, we retain information regarding the value of the order placed within the data log and on the advert placement record. Please see clause 6 below regarding the information that you submit to payment providers in connection with your advertisement on Car Trader;

2.3.7

2.3.8 phone calls may be recorded by us from time to time; and

2.3.9 details of advertisements and enquiries you submit through Car Trader, our inbound SMS service or any other means.

## USES MADE OF THE INFORMATION

3.1 Advertisers partake in Cartrader by placing advertisements for Vehicles for sale. Advertisers are able to manage, change, and remove the advertisements submitted to Cartrader. Services trough Sell my Car”Advertisers need personal login details to access“Sell my Car” which will have been supplied to them on completion of registration with Car Trader.

3.2 Advertisements contain information relating to Vehicles and also limited personal information about Advertisers which Advertisers provide to us. You agree that if you place an advertisement on Car Trader then we can provide potential buyers with the telephone number that you provide to us via Car Trader. You acknowledge and agree that you may be contacted using that number by Car Trader users.

3.3 We require Car Trader users responding to **Advertisements via Car Trader Namibia** to provide their name, email address, comments addressed to the Advertiser and (optionally) a telephone number to us. Then we email the Advertiser on their behalf, and give the Advertiser this information. Advertisers agree that they will only use the information that we provide to them from Car Trader users for the purposes of dealing with their Advertisement, unless the Car Trader user separately agrees with the Advertiser.

3.4 Separately, Car Trader users can contact the Advertiser directly via an "email the seller" button on Car Trader which allows the Car Trader user to send the Advertiser a message via Car Trader directly. You agree to only contact an Advertiser using Car Trader or using information that we give to you for the purposes of dealing with the Advertiser's Advertisement, unless the Car Trader user separately agrees with the Advertiser

3.5 We use information held about you in the following ways:

3.5.1 to develop relevant content from Car Trader and ensure that content is presented in the most effective manner for you and for your computer;

3.5.2 to provide you with information (such as information on offers and competitions), products or services that you request from us or which we feel may interest you including information (such as information on offers and competitions) from us, and our selected partners, and to notify you about changes to our service, where you have consented to be contacted for such purposes;

3.5.3 to carry out our obligations arising from any contracts entered into between you and us;

3.5.4 to deliver and maintain a high quality service;

3.5.5 to assist you if you are experiencing a problem with Car Trader;

3.5.6 to allow you to access Car Trader and to participate in interactive features of our service, when you choose to do so;

3.5.7 to conduct market research by telephone as part of a survey of our services, you will be able to choose whether or not you want to take part in surveys; and

3.5.8 for the purposes of compiling statistics.

3.6 Except as set out in this Privacy Policy, we do not sell, rent, share, trade or give away any of your personal information.

## DISCLOSURE OF YOUR INFORMATION TO OTHER PEOPLE

4.1 We do not disclose to any third party personal information that you provide to us unless we have your permission or we believe the law permits or requires it.

4.2 If you provide personal information to us you understand and agree that we may disclose your personal information to the following third parties:

4.2.1

4.2.2 any member of our group of companies, which means our subsidiaries, our ultimate holding company and its subsidiaries;

4.2.3

4.2.4 to the prospective seller or buyer of any business or assets related to Car Trader or any other member of our group of companies;

4.2.5 to a third party if we are under a duty to disclose or share your personal data with that third party in order to comply with any legal obligation, or in order to enforce or apply our terms of use and other agreements, or to protect the rights, property, or safety of our group of companies, Car Trader, our customers, other registered users or others. This includes exchanging information with third parties for the purposes of fraud protection and credit risk reduction.

4.3 While we do not disclose your name to third party vehicle record checking service providers, when you ask us to check registration details of your vehicle or where we think it is prudent to do so, we may send limited details such as your vehicle's registration number to these services providers.

4.4 Where legally required to do so we will notify you when information about you may be provided to third parties in ways other than explained in this policy, and you will have the option to prevent such information sharing at the time that we notify you.

## SECURITY AND CONTROL OF YOUR PERSONAL DATA

5.1 We will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

5.2 Where we have given you (or where you have chosen) a password which enables you to access certain parts of Car Trader, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential. We ask you not to share a password with anyone. You are responsible for the security of your password and our Terms and Conditions deal with this in more detail.

5.3 Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the Internet is not completely secure. Although we will do our best to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee the security of your data transmitted to Car Trader; any transmission is at your own risk. Once we have received your information, we will use strict procedures and security features to try to prevent unauthorized access. You acknowledge that we are not responsible for any intercepted information sent via the Internet, and you hereby release us from any and all claims arising out of or related to the use of intercepted information in any unauthorized manner.

5.4 You should be aware that when you voluntarily disclose personally identifiable information and agree to make that information public on Car Trader (e.g., telephone number) via advertisements on Car Trader or where you use Car Trader to correspond with other users or Advertisers, that information, along with any substantive information disclosed in your advertisement, can be collected, correlated and used by third parties. These third parties, other Advertisers or Car Trader users may use your information to send you unsolicited messages. Such activities are beyond our control. Please do not post any personal information on Car Trader which will be published on Car Trader that you wish to keep private. Please consider carefully what personal information you wish to send other users or Advertisers on Car Trader.

## LINKS TO THIRD PARTY WEBSITES AND ADVERTISEMENTS ON THIRD PARTY WEBSITES

6.1 Car Trader may, from time to time, contain links to and from the websites of our partner networks, advertisers and affiliates as well as third party websites to which we have no affiliation.

6.2 If you follow a link to any of these websites, please note that these websites may have their own privacy policies and/or terms and conditions which apply to them, and that we do not accept any responsibility or liability for these policies, terms and conditions or for the activities on those websites.

6.3 From time to time we may enter into arrangements with third parties where the third parties agree to display your Advertisement on their website or to publish it in their publications (whether offline or online). You agree and understand that where we do this any personal data that you have chosen to include in your Advertisement will be provided to the third party for this purpose when we supply the content of the Advertisement to them. Please note that these third party websites and publications may have their own privacy policies and/or terms and conditions which apply to them, and that we do not accept any responsibility or liability for these policies, terms and conditions or for the activities on those websites or in connection with those publications.

## IP ADDRESSES, TRAFFIC DATA, LOCATION DATA AND COOKIES

7.1 We may collect information about your computer, including (where available) alphanumeric IDs, operating system, browser type and traffic data, such as information regarding the volume and status of data transmission, click-through statistics, the name of the domain and host from which you access the Internet and the date and time you access portions of the Car Trader ("Website Use Info"), for system administration and statistical purposes. This Website Use Info is statistical data about our users' browsing actions and patterns, and does not identify any individual, except if required by the law. We retain Website Use Info for a limited period of 12 Months after which the data is deleted.

7.2 We may also collect information about your IP address and geographic location ("Geo Data") for system administration and statistical purposes. You can turn off our ability to tailor what you see on Car Trader by our using the Geo Data that we gather about you via Car Trader by enabling the appropriate settings on your computer or browser or contacting us directly. For example:

7.2.1 [On Internet Explorer, please follow Tools, Internet Options, Privacy and select the appropriate settings.

7.2.2 On Mozilla Firefox, please follow Tools, Options, Privacy Panel and select the appropriate settings.

7.2.3 On Google Chrome, please select the wrench icon, Options (Preferences on Mac and Linux; Settings on a Chromebook), and select the appropriate settings.]

7.3 For the same reason, we may obtain information about your general internet usage by using a cookie file which is stored on the hard drive of your computer. Cookies contain information that is transferred to your computer's hard drive. On revisiting Car Trader our computer server will recognize the cookie, giving us information about your last visit. They help us to improve Car Trader and to deliver a better and more personalized service.

## ACCESS TO INFORMATION AND UPDATING, VERIFYING AND DELETING PERSONAL DATA

8.1 At any time, you can make a written request to have access to and/or delete all personal information that we hold about you. We will provide this information to you and may request a small administrative charge.

8.2 As an Advertiser, you can modify or update or delete your personal information at any time by accessing your account on Car Trader and choosing the option "Edit details" or by contacting us at classifieds@Car Trader.

## CHANGES TO OUR PRIVACY POLICY

9.1 Any changes we may make to our Privacy Policy in the future will be posted on this page and, where appropriate, notified to you by e-mail. You should visit this page periodically to review any changes to the Privacy Policy.

9.2 Advertisers will be notified upon accessing their account of any substantial changes to our Privacy Policy and Terms and Conditions. Use of Car Trader by Advertisers is conditional on the acceptance of our Privacy Policy and Terms and Conditions.
